

□ 07805 871708 |

thetrianglegirl@gmail.com |
trianglegirl.rbind.io | Intrianglegirl

Key Points _

Education PhD in Statistics and Operational Research.

Data Science Experience Unilever, Arctic Shores and Digital Rail.

Engagement Statistical Ambassador for the RSS. Regular outreach with public and schools.

R Skills University R Tutor. Skilled at Tidyverse, Shiny, RMarkdown.

Experience _____

Digital Rail Ltd

DATA SCIENTIST 2018 - Present

- Develop analytical techniques and visualisation apps for the railway industry.
- Provide statistical consultancy for a broad range of clients.
- · Supervision of multiple student projects.

Arctic Shores

DATA SCIENTIST 2017 - 2018

- Developed psychometric models for game-based assessment.
- Data processing and analysis alongside model validation.
- Supported psychologists transition from SPSS to R.

Unilever Research and Development

DATA EXPERT Mar 2015 - Sep 2015

- Established computational methods to extract features from accelerometers.
- Responsible for the processing and analysis of experimental study data.

University of Lancaster

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT 2012 - 2017

- Taught a broad range of undergraduate mathematics and statistics courses.
- Tutored R programming to undergraduates, postgraduates and industry.

Education

University of Lancaster

PhD Statistics and Operational Research

2012 - 2017

- My thesis was titled Efficient Analysis of Data Streams.
- My research focused on online clustering, spectral clustering, classification, image processing, image segmentation and identifying points of change in time series.

University of Lancaster

MRES STATISTICS AND OPERATIONAL RESEARCH

2011 - 2012

· Covered a range of topics, including Likelihood and Bayesian Statistics, MCMC Methods, Machine Learning techniques, Optimisation and Data Mining.

University of Lancaster

BSc Mathematics and Statistics, First Class

2009 - 2011

Extracurricular Activity

R-Ladies Lancaster

CO-FOUNDER & ORGANISER 2018 - Present

• Organising and delivering talks to support people using the R language.

Royal Statistical Society

STATISTICAL AMBASSADOR & FELLOW

2015 - Present

- Engaging with the media, schools and wider public to improve statistical literacy.
- Chair of the Lancashire and East Cumbria branch.
- Currently working towards CStat status.

STEMNET

STEM AMBASSADOR 2013 - Present

- Active and passionate STEM engager.
- Invited talks include Royal Institute Masterclass & Florence Nightingale Day.
- Developed and delivered statistics summer school for college students.

Key skills ___

R Expertise RStudio, RMarkdown, Tidyverse, Shiny **Machine Learning** Statistical modelling, Clustering, Classification

Awards & Grants _____

2014 **Grant leader**, STOR-i research fund - UCLID conference £6,000

2013 **Best Paper Award**, Sensor Data Fusion Workshop Bonn, Germany

2011 **Grant leader**, UniBrass - Arts Council Funding

£10,000

Interests _

Professional R programming, machine learning, data visualising, attending data science meet-ups, image processing.

Personal Cycling, fell running, knitting, orchestral percussion.